[×](javascript:acceptCookiePolicy())

We use cookies to help make LingQ better. By visiting the site, you agree to our [cookie policy](https://www.lingq.com/en/cookie-policy/).

Display Language: **en**

* English
* Spanish
* German
* French
* Italian
* Portuguese
* Japanese
* Chinese (Simplified)
* Chinese (Traditional)
* Korean
* Russian
* Swedish
* Turkish
* Dutch
* Lithuanian
* Greek
* Polish
* Ukrainian

Privacy Policy
==============

Effective Date: 25 May 2018

LingQ respects your privacy and shares your concern about the security of information you may submit to LingQ’s websites and the related mobile applications and services (collectively, the “Services”). Our privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”) explains the information we collect, how we use and share it, how to manage your privacy settings and your rights in connection with the Services. Please also read the [Terms of Service](https://www.lingq.com/en/terms/) which sets out the terms governing the Services.

LingQ is headquartered in West Vancouver, Canada and our Services are provided to you by LingQ Languages Ltd (LingQ). If you are a resident of the European Union (“EU”), The Linguist Institute, is the controller of your personal data for the purposes of EU data protection law.

This policy was written in English. To the extent a translated version conflicts with the English version, the English version controls. Unless indicated otherwise, this Privacy Policy does not apply to third party products or services or the practices of companies that we do not own or control, including other companies you might interact with on or through the Services.

Questions or comments about this Privacy Policy may be submitted by mail to the address below or by emailing [LingQ Support](mailto:support@lingq.com).

LingQ Languages Ltd (LingQ)  
200-2232 Marine Drive  
West Vancouver, BC  
Canada V7V 1K4  

Information LingQ Collects
--------------------------

LingQ collects information about you, including information that directly or indirectly identifies you, if you or your other members choose to share it with LingQ. We receive information in a few different ways, including when you track, complete or upload activities using the Services. LingQ also collects information about how you use the Services. There are also several opportunities for you to share information about yourself and your activities with LingQ. For example:

* We collect **basic account information** such as your name, email address, username and password that helps secure and provide you with access to our Services.
* **Profile and use information** is collected about you when you choose to upload a picture, shaare a lesson, or post on the Exchange or Forum, join a challenge, add your profile information, or otherwise use the Services.
* You can choose to add your **contacts’ information** to connect with your contacts on LingQ and to send them your activity information while using our referrals tool. If you choose to use these features, LingQ does not store your contacts’ information but simply sends emails one time only. By submitting such contact information, you confirm that you have the authority to use and share such information.
* When you make a payment on LingQ, you may provide **payment information** such as your payment card or other payment details. We use Payment Card Industry compliant third-party payment services and we do not store your credit card information.
* We ask you to input your time zone and native language information in order to better offer services like showing available tutoring times in your local time zone and offering translations in your native language.
* LingQ allows you to sign up and log in to the Services using accounts you create with third-party products and services, such as Facebook or Google (collectively, “Third-Party Accounts”). If you access the Services with **Third-Party Accounts** we will collect information that you have agreed to make available such as your name, email address, profile information and preferences with the applicable Third-Party Account. This information is collected by the Third-Party Account provider and is provided to LingQ under their privacy policies. You can generally control the information that we receive from these sources using the privacy settings in your Third-Party Account.
* To help us to provide you with the best possible service, you can choose to provide us with your **contact information** so we can better respond to your support requests and comments.
* We also obtain additional **third party information** about members from marketers, partners, researchers, and others. We may combine information that we collect from you with information obtained from other members, third parties and information derived from any other subscription, product, or service we provide. We may also collect **information about you from other members** such as when they give you Likes or comment about you.
* We collect information from your browser, computer, or mobile device, which provide us with **technical information** when you access or use the Services. This technical information includes device and network information, cookies, log files and analytics information.

Cookies and Similar Technologies
--------------------------------

When you visit the Services, a cookie will be stored on your computer. Generally, cookies and similar technologies work by assigning to your browser or device a unique number that has no meaning outside of LingQ. LingQ uses these technologies to personalize your experience and to assist in delivering content specific to your interests. Additionally, after you’ve entered your member ID and password during a session on the Services, LingQ saves that information so you don’t have to re-enter it repeatedly during that session.

Most browsers automatically accept cookies. To manage the collection of information through cookies or other equivalent technology you can use the settings on your browser or mobile device. LingQ is committed to providing you choices to manage your privacy and sharing. However, LingQ does not recognize or respond to browser-initiated Do Not Track signals, as the internet industry has not fully developed Do Not Track standards, implementations and solutions. To learn more about Do Not Track signals, you can visit [https://allaboutdnt.com](https://allaboutdnt.com/). Not accepting cookies may make certain features of the Services unavailable to you. LingQ may also use your IP address to identify you, to administer the Services and to assist in diagnosing problems with LingQ’s servers.

Log Files
---------

The Services use log files. Stored information includes IP addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. This information is used to analyze trends, administer, protect and secure the Services, track member movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc., may be linked to session IDs, user IDs and device identifiers.

How LingQ Uses Information
--------------------------

LingQ uses the information we collect and receive to administer and operate the Services and as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. For example, we use your learning information to provide you with statistics and visualizations representing key data points like known words. Your information, including your profile, username, photos, members you follow and who follow you, groups you belong to, your activities, and likes and comments you give and receive will be shared on LingQ to participate in the Services, for example to show your place in the rankings.

We also use your information to analyze, develop and improve the Services. To do this, LingQ may use third party analytics providers to gain insights into how our Services are used and to help us improve the Services. We may also use your information to market the Services, credit or accept payments, provide support related to the Services, protect members and enforce our [Terms of Service](https://www.lingq.com/en/terms/), promote safety, and communicate with you. Additionally, your information may be shared with third parties, as set forth below.

LingQ may de-identify or aggregate the content you make available in connection with the Services, in ways that do not personally identify you. Examples of such aggregated information or statistical data include information about equipment, usage, demographics, languages and performance. LingQ may use, sell, license, and share this information with third parties for research, business or other purposes such as to improve language acquisition. Please visit your privacy settings if you object to LingQ using your information for these purposes.

We use your information to communicate with you about the Services, send you marketing communications (where you have agreed to receive such messages), or let you know about new features or updates to our [Terms of Service](https://www.lingq.com/en/terms/). We also use your information to respond to you when you contact us. LingQ will use your information to communicate with you, for example by sending you notifications.

How Information is Shared
-------------------------

### Service Providers

We may share your information with third parties who provide services to LingQ such as supporting and improving the Services, promoting the Services, processing payments, or fulfilling orders. These service providers will only have access to the information necessary to perform these limited functions on our behalf and are required to protect and secure your information. We may also engage service providers to collect information about your use of the Services over time on our behalf so that we or they may promote LingQ or display information that may be relevant to your interests on the Services or other websites or services.

### Publicly Available Information

Subject to your privacy settings, your information and content may be publicly accessible.

### Third Party Business via API or Other Integrations

When you choose to use third party apps, plug-ins, or websites that integrate with the Services, they may receive your information and content, including your personal information, photos, and your activity data (including private activities). Information collected by these third parties is subject to their terms and policies. LingQ is not responsible for the terms or policies of third parties.

### Affiliates and Acquirors of our Business or Assets

We may share your information with affiliates under common control with us, who are required to comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy with regard to your information. If LingQ becomes involved in a business combination, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, dissolution or other similar transaction, we may share or transfer your information in connection with such transaction.

### Legal Requirements

We may preserve and share your information with third parties, including law enforcement, public or governmental agencies, or private litigants, within or outside your country of residence, if we determine that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with the law, including to respond to court orders, warrants, subpoenas, or other legal or regulatory process. We may also retain, preserve or disclose your information if we determine that disclosure is reasonably necessary or appropriate to prevent any person from death or serious bodily injury, to address issues of national security or other issues of public importance, to prevent or detect violations of our [Terms of Service](https://www.lingq.com/en/terms/) or fraud or abuse of LingQ or its members, or to protect our operations or our property or other legal rights, including by disclosure to our legal counsel and other consultants and third parties in connection with actual or potential litigation.

### DMCA Notices

We may share your information with third parties when we forward Digital Millennium Copyright Act (DMCA) notifications, which will be forwarded as submitted to us without any deletions.

How We Protect Information
--------------------------

We take several measures to safeguard the collection, transmission and storage of the data we collect. Although we strive to employ reasonable protections for your information that are appropriate to its sensitivity, we do not guarantee or warrant the security of the information you share with us and we are not responsible for the theft, destruction, loss or inadvertent disclosure of your information or content. No system is 100% secure. The Services uses industry standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to allow for the encryption of personal information and credit card numbers. LingQ engages a company that is an industry leader in online security and Services verification to strengthen the security of LingQ’s Services. The Services are registered with site identification authorities so that your browser can confirm LingQ’s identity before any personally identifiable information is sent. In addition, LingQ’s secure servers protect this information using advanced firewall technology.

To help ensure that these measures are effective in preventing unauthorized access to your private information, you should be aware of the security features available to you through your browser. You should use a security-enabled browser to submit your credit card information and other personal information at the Services. Please note that if you do not use a SSL-capable browser, you are at risk for having data intercepted.

Most browsers have the ability to notify you if you change between secure and insecure communications, receive invalid services identification information for the Services you are communicating with, or send information over an unsecured connection. LingQ recommends that you enable these browser functions to help ensure that your communications are secure. You can also monitor the URL of the services you are visiting (secure URLs begin with https:// rather than http://), along with the security symbol of your browser to help identify when you are communicating with a secure server. You can also view the details of the security certificate of the services to which you are connected. Please check the validity of any Services you connect to using secure communications.

### Disclaimer

While LingQ continues to work hard to protect your personal information, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be absolutely secure, and LingQ cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to LingQ. Transmitting personal information is done at your own risk.

Managing Your Settings
----------------------

### Adjust Notification and Email Preferences

LingQ offers various ways to manage the notifications you receive. You can choose to stop receiving certain emails and notifications by indicating your preference at [https://www.lingq.com/en/settings/notifications-email](https://www.lingq.com/en/settings/notifications-email). You may also unsubscribe by following the instructions contained at the bottom of each type of email. Any administrative or service-related emails (to confirm a purchase, or an update to this Privacy Policy or the [Terms of Service](https://www.lingq.com/en/terms/), etc.) generally do not offer an option to unsubscribe as they are necessary to provide the Services you requested.

### Updating Account Information

You may correct, amend or update profile or account information that is inaccurate at any time by adjusting that information in your account settings. If you need further assistance, please contact LingQ at [support@LingQ.com](mailto:support@lingq.com). LingQ will generally respond to your request within 7-10 business days.

### Deleting Information and Accounts

You may request that your account is deleted by visiting [https://www.lingq.com/settings/account](https://www.lingq.com/settings/#account). Once deleted, your data, including your account, activities and place on leaderboards cannot be reinstated.

Note that content you have shared with others (for example, through lessons) or that others have copied may also remain visible after you have deleted your account or deleted the information from your own profile. Your public profile may be displayed in search engine results until the search engine refreshes its cache.

EU Members’ Rights
------------------

If you are habitually located in the European Union, you have the right to access, rectify, download or erase your information, as well as the right to restrict and object to certain processing of your information. While some of these rights apply generally, certain rights apply only in certain limited circumstances. We describe these rights below:

* #### Access and Porting
    
    You can access much of your information by logging into your account. If you require additional access or if you are not a LingQ member, contact us at support@lingq.com. To download a copy of your data, contact us at [support@LingQ.com](mailto:support@lingq.com).
* #### Rectify, Restrict, Limit, Delete
    
    You can also rectify, restrict, limit or delete much of your information by logging into your account. If you are unable to do this, please contact us at [support@LingQ.com](mailto:support@lingq.com). LingQ will generally respond to your request within 10-14 business days.
* #### Object
    
    Where we process your information based on our legitimate interests explained above, or in the public interest, you can object to this processing in certain circumstances. In such cases, we will cease processing your information unless we have compelling legitimate grounds to continue processing or where it is needed for legal reasons.
* #### Revoke consent
    
    Where you have previously provided your consent, such as to permit us to process language related data about you, you have the right to withdraw your consent to the processing of your information at any time. For example, you can withdraw your consent by emailing support@lingq.com. In certain cases, we may continue to process your information after you have withdrawn consent if we have a legal basis to do so or if your withdrawal of consent was limited to certain processing activities.
* #### Complain
    
    Should you wish to raise a concern about our use of your information (and without prejudice to any other rights you may have), you have the right to do so with your local supervisory authority.

Transfers
---------

The Services are operated from the United States. If you are located outside of the United States and choose to use the Services or provide information to us, you acknowledge and understand that your information will be transferred, processed and stored in the United States, as it is necessary to provide the Services and perform the [Terms of Service](https://www.lingq.com/en/terms/). United States privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction.

Retention of Information
------------------------

We retain information as long as it is necessary to provide the Services to you and others, subject to any legal obligations to further retain such information. Information associated with your account will generally be kept until it is no longer necessary to provide the Services or until you ask us to delete it or your account is deleted whichever comes first. For example, where you withdraw your consent to LingQ processing your language learning information, LingQ will delete all language learning related information you uploaded. Following your deletion of your account, it may take up to 30 days to fully delete your personal information and system logs from our systems. Additionally, we may retain information from deleted accounts to comply with the law, prevent fraud, collect fees, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with investigations, enforce the [Terms of Service](https://www.lingq.com/en/terms/) and take other actions permitted by law. The information we retain will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Information about you that is no longer necessary and relevant to provide our Services may be de-identified and aggregated with other non-personal data to provide insights which are commercially valuable to LingQ, such as statistics of the use of the Services. For example, we may retain popular lesson usage information, topic information and other depersonalized preference information to continue to improve the Services and to improve the Lesson Feed and provision of suitable content. This information will be de-associated with your name and other identifiers.

Other LingQ Sites
-----------------

LingQ maintains certain websites that can be accessed outside of [https://www.LingQ.com](https://www.lingq.com/), such as [https://www.LingQ.com/blog](https://www.lingq.com/blog), [https://www.thelinguist.com](https://www.thelinguist.com/), [https://blog.thelinguist.com](https://blog.thelinguist.com/) (the “Other Sites”). The Other Sites maintain the look and feel of the Services, but are hosted by outside service providers with their own terms and privacy policies. If you interact with the Other Sites, your information may be stored, processed, or shared outside of the Services. If you interact with the Other Sites, you acknowledge that you may be subject to the terms and conditions and policies applicable to such Other Site. Please be aware that any personal information you submit to the Other Sites may be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums indefinitely, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. LingQ is not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit via the Other Sites.

Privacy Policy Information
--------------------------

LingQ reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. Please review it occasionally. If LingQ makes changes to this Privacy Policy, the updated Privacy Policy will be posted on the Services in a timely manner and, if we make material changes, we will provide a prominent notice. If you object to any of the changes to this Privacy Policy, you should stop using the Services and [delete your account](https://www.lingq.com/en/accounts/cancel/).

© 2018 LingQ

=====================================

Get our App at:
---------------

© 2002-2024 [LingQ Languages Ltd.](https://www.lingq.com/en/about/) All rights reserved. 200-2232 Marine Drive, West Vancouver, BC, Canada V7V 1K4
